# PETER BENVENUTO

## SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Product Designer | Mozilla

MAY 2021 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

- Conducting discovery, research and execution of major features for core products within our team (from ideation to conception)
- Leading org-wide design system audit, rebuild and maintenance
- Assisting with communication of strategy with key stakeholders
- Help run candidate interviews across broader team

## Product Designer | Intrado

MAR 2021 - MAY 2021, TORONTO, ON

- Conducting user research and user testing for core SaaS products
- Leading UX/UI design initiatives while following human-centered design thinking best practices
- Collaborating closely with product owners and developers in an agile environment

## Software Engineer | InvestCloud Inc.

SEP 2018 - MAR 2021, BURLINGTON, ON

- Developed and shipped products using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Develop efficient ETL scripts in Groovy/Java to extract, compute and map client focused financial data
- Design RESTful web APIs to seamlessly extract client data from existing CRM systems

#### **UX/UI Engineer | PlayLine**

JUL 2018 - SEP 2018 (CONTRACT), TORONTO, ON

- Maintaining and shipping new features using React and Redux
- Liaised with design team when making design decisions

#### **MENTORING & TEACHING**

#### UX Mentor & Instructor | BrainStation

NOV 2022 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

#### Front End Development Tutor | CareerFoundry

FEB 2022 - PRESENT, REMOTE

## **EDUCATION**

#### BrainStation | Diploma, User Experience Design

SEP 2020 - DEC 2020, TORONTO, ON

#### Humber College | Postgraduate Diploma, Marketing

SEP 2016 - 2017, TORONTO, ON

#### York University | Bachelors, Political Science

SEP 2011 - 2014, TORONTO, ON

peterbenvenuto90@gmail.com 416-456-3019 linkedin.com/in/peter-benvenuto github.com/PeterBen90 peterbenvenuto.com

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a Product Designer based in Toronto, ON. I approach problems with a data-informed and empathetic approach, and I have a unique background in software development. My experience allows me to communicate and work with developers effectively in product teams. I specialize in Interaction Design, Design Systems, and Design Strategy.

#### **DESIGN SKILLS**

Design User research and testing, Information architecture, Wireframing, UI prototyping, Interaction design, Motion design, Responsive design, Design systems, Visual design, Figma, Sketch, InVision, InVision Studio, Zeplin, Zeroheight, Adobe Creative Suite

#### **DEV SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Redux, Material UI, Bootstrap, Bulma, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Java, Groovy, PostgreSQL, SQL, Git, Responsive design

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Software Engineering - Thinkful Enterprise Design Thinking - IBM